I will now name
the successor to Ninshu.
(ハゴロモ)では これより
忍宗の後継者を発表する。
忍宗の後継者は…。
The one who shall take over
Ninshu will be…
アシュラに任せる。
Ashura!
(アシュラ)えっ!?
(インドラ)なっ！
(フタミ)ハ… ハゴロモ様！
(アシュラ)なぜです!?
L-Lord Hagoromo!
Why?!
私には 兄さんほどの
忍宗の才はありません！
I have nowhere near the skills for
Ninshu that Elder Brother has!
The difference is immeasurable!
I've made my decision.
(ハゴロモ)これは 決めたことだ。
(インドラ)なぜ 私では不満なのか
その理由をお聞かせください。
Please tell me why you were
dissatisfied with me.
お前に任せた村は 今
壊滅状態にあるとの報告を受けた。
I received word that the village
I had left you in charge of
is near destruction.
そんな… どうして!?
What? How?!
まさか 神樹を無理やり…。
You didn't forcibly use
the Divine Tree to…
私が そこまで愚かに見えるか？
Do I look like a fool?
何をしたのか 話してみよ。
Tell me what you did.
私がやったことも
アシュラと同じです。
I did the same thing Ashura did.
I gave the people the water
they desired…
望みどおり 村の者たちに
水を与え 神樹を処分した。
and dealt with the Divine Tree.
ただ 違うのは 私は
１人でやった ということです。
The only difference was that…
I did it alone.
それが 大きく結果を変えたのだ。
And that drastically affected the result.
村の人間たちは 水の利権を争い
自らの身を滅ぼしたそうだ。
After you left,
the villagers fought over water rights
and ended up destroying themselves.
楽をして 手にした幸福は
長続きはしないものだ。
Happiness obtained with
the easy way never lasts long.
だが アシュラは 村の人々とともに
苦難の道を歩いた。
But Ashura labored alongside
the people to open up a path.
Hard-earned happiness
is difficult to destroy.
苦難のすえに手にした幸福は
そう簡単には崩れはしない。
インドラ… お前には 写輪眼という
すばらしい力がある。
Indra, you have a wonderful power
known as the Sharingan.
アシュラは成長したといえど
まだ 力は足りない。
Ashura has matured,
but still lacks in power.
Lend him your power going forward
and support the growth of Ninshu.
これから先
忍宗を支えていくために→
アシュラに力を貸してやってくれ。
兄さん…。
Elder Brother…
The Successor
((インドラ : なぜだ…
なぜ 俺が選ばれない？
Why?
Why didn't he choose me?
そのとおりだ！
Exactly!
The one with power rules the world!
That's just common sense!
力がある者が世界を制するのは
当たり前のことだ！
Indra has the power
to decide everything!
インドラには すべてを
決めるだけの力があるじゃないか。
Let's appeal to
Lord Hagoromo again.
今から もう一度
ハゴロモ様に かけ合ってみようぜ。
We'll support you!
俺たちも力を貸す。
Thanks, both of you.
(インドラ)すまない ２人とも。
いいんだ。 俺は ただ
お前の力になりたいだけだ。
No need for thanks.
We just want to support you.
あぁ なんでも言ってくれ。
Yes, just tell us anything
that you want us to do!
そうか…。
Really?
This is amazing!
(タイゾウ)うひょ～！
こんなご馳走 見たことねえ!!
I've never seen such a feast!
今日は 忍宗の後継者が決まった
めでたい日だ。
Today is the auspicious day
the successor of Ninshu was chosen!
Everyone, eat and enjoy
to your heart's content!
みんな！ 無礼講で
心ゆくまで楽しんでくれ。
食おうぜ みんな！
Let's eat, everyone!
I think we came at a bad time.
(カンナ)なんだか 私たち
大変なときに来ちゃったみたいね。
ヘッ！ 気にすること ねえよ。
Don't worry about it.
実は 俺 ほっとしてるんだ
後継者が アシュラに決まって。
To be honest, I'm relieved.
That Ashura was chosen
to be the successor.
えっ？
Ashura's big brother is smart
and he's a genius with Ninshu,
(タイゾウ)アシュラの兄さんは 頭もいいし
忍宗の才能も すごいけど→
but there's a coldness to him.
どっか
冷たいところがある人でさ…。
あの人が 忍宗 継いだら
みんな 心のどっかで→
If he was named successor,
I think we'd all be scared of him.
ビクビクしてなきゃ
ならなかったと思う。
I see.
そうなんだ。
でも アシュラなら人の痛みがわかる。
But Ashura understands a person's pain.
ちょっとマヌケだけど 今度の旅で
あいつは すごく成長した。
He's a bit dense, but this last journey
really matured him.
お前が惚れ込んで ここまで
ついてくるくらいにさ。
Enough to make you
fall in love with him
and follow him all the way here.
W-What're you saying?!
何言ってんのよ。
赤くなってんぞ。
You're blushing.
バカ！
あっ…。
You idiot!
Ouch!
もう。
Really…
Hey, where is Ashura anyway?
そういえば アシュラ
どこ行ったんだろう？
アシュラか。
Ashura…
納得いかぬか？
はい。
You're not satisfied?
Yes.
インドラは変わってしまった。
写輪眼のせいでな。
Indra has changed…
It's because of the Sharingan.
写輪眼が？
Sharingan?
インドラの写輪眼を見た
誰もが その力に圧倒される。
Everyone who sees Sharingan is
overwhelmed by its power.
インドラ本人も気づかぬうちにな。
And that happened
way before Indra realized it.
それほどに インドラの写輪眼は
強力なのだ。
That's how powerful
Indra's Sharingan is.
その力ゆえに いつしか本人も
人の心を理解することをやめ→
That power stopped Indra from
understanding how others feel…
ついに
インドラの心は閉じてしまった。
And in the end, it closed his heart.
だが お前は違う。
But you are different.
お前は人々の心を理解できる。
You understand the human heart.
ゆえに愛をもって忍宗を生かした。
That is why you enhanced
Ninshu with love.
And that nurtured trust among people,
created bonds and friendship.
それが人々の信頼を生み
絆を生み 仲間を生んだ。
仲間…。
Friendship?
絆とは多くの苦楽をともにし→
A bond is only created after
sharing hardship together.
初めて生まれるものだ。
A bond overflows with love
and compassion.
絆には愛と情が溢れている。
絆があるかぎり 忍宗が
悪用されることはない。
As long as there are bonds,
Ninshu will not be used for evil.
だが 絆なき力は→
However, power without bonds will
bring about calamity in the world.
いずれ世界に災いを起こす。
アシュラよ。
Ashura…
お前は兄とともに ２人力を合わせ
忍宗の絆を広めるのだ。
Join forces with your brother and
spread the bonds of Ninshu.
父上。
Father…
これより お前に
わしの力を託す！
From this moment onward,
I entrust my power to you.
アシュラ。
Ashura!
もう どこ行ったのかしら。
Where did he go?
えっ…。
何 あれ？
What is that?!
(みんな)うわ～。
な 何だ？
W-What is it?
カンナ 大丈夫か？
Kanna! Are you all right?
ええ。
いったい…。
Yes…
What just happened?
兄さん。
Elder Brother!
インドラ これはどういうことだ？
Indra…
What is the meaning of this?
なぜだ なぜ俺が
後継者に選ばれない？
Why?
Why didn't you choose me
as your successor?
忍宗を統べるのは力ではなく愛。
そう決めたのだ。
It isn't power that
controls Ninshu, but love.
That is what I have decided.
愛だと？ 愛など必要ない。
Love?
There is no need for love!
あの旅のとき
俺もアシュラと同じように→
During my journey,
like Ashura,
I searched for the villagers' pain.
村人たちに痛みを求めた。
しかし 村の連中は
結局 俺の力にすがったのだ。
But ultimately, the villagers
ended up relying on my power.
弱き者たちは
俺を王と崇め 力を求めた。
The weak revered me as their king
and wanted my power.
アシュラは未熟だったゆえに→
Ashura was lacking.
他人の協力を必要と
せざるをえなかっただけだ。
That is why he found it necessary
to get the cooperation of others.
だが 俺は違う！
But I'm different!
弱き者の助けなどいらない。
I don't need the help of the weak.
この力を使い 力による
完全なる秩序をつくる。
I can use my power
and I can establish total order!
争いのない完全なる世界だ。
A world completely
devoid of conflict!
それでは
我が母上 カグヤと同じだ。
That's just like my mother, Kaguya…
力を持つ者こそ
心を忘れてはならんのだ。
Especially those with power,
must never forget the human heart.
人々は
お前ほど早く進むことはできぬ。
People cannot progress
as swiftly as you can.
歩みを
同じくできぬ者たちにとって→
Those who cannot walk
at the same pace
絆なき力とは恐怖でしかない。
can only fear power
that has no bond.
人々は恐怖による統治では
従わない。
People will not support
governance through fear.
なら力ずくで従わせるだけだ。
Then I shall force them to obey.
やめてください 兄さん。
Please stop, Elder Brother!
兄さんは 俺の命を
守ってくれるくらい→
You would have given
your life to protect me.
優しかったじゃないか！
That's how kind you once were!
アシュラ
あの頃の俺とは違う。
Ashura…
I am no longer that man.
もう後戻りはできぬのだ。
I cannot return to being him.
(インドラ その目は！))
Indra…
Your eyes!
((俺は ただお前の力に
なりたいだけだ。
We just want to support you.
ああ なんでも言ってくれ。
(インドラ)そうか。
Yes, just tell us anything
that you want us to do!
Really?
Thank you, both of you.
ありがとう ２人とも。
うう！
インドラ…。
どうして…。
Indra… Why?!
(すまない))
Forgive me…
《親しい者を失ったとき
写輪眼は進化する》
Whenever I lose the ones
closest and dear to me…
my Sharingan evolves.
((インドラ そこまで堕ちたか。
Indra!
So you've stooped that low…
もうやめてください
俺は兄さんとは戦いたくない。
Please stop!
I don't want to fight you, Elder Brother!
ほう 俺と戦うだと？
Oh…fight me?
ずいぶんと偉くなったな アシュラ。
You've become quite brave, Ashura!
お前が 俺の相手になると
思っているのか？
You really think
you can take me on?
何!?
うお～ は～！
What?!
す すごい。
修業の成果だぜ！
A-Amazing!
That's the result of his training!
な…。
少しは できるようになったか。
You've become quite brave, Ashura!
(だが その程度では
私には勝てん！))
But it's not enough to beat me!
((いくぞ。
Here I come.
これが力だ！
This is power!
うわ～っ！
Ashura?!
アシュラ！
父上！ みんな！
Father!
Everyone!
皆 力を合わせるのだ！
Join forces!
(みんな)うお～っ！
この俺に刃向かうとは。
You have the audacity
to point your blade at me?
(みんな)うわっ！
フン… 力のない連中が
群れたところで 意味などない。
The powerless can band together,
but it means nothing.
父上
あなたの言う脆弱な理想に 今→
Father, let me perform the last rites
for your fragile ideals!
引導を渡してやる。
終わりだ！
兄さん！
It's over!
Elder Brother!
ん？
これは…。
This is…
六道の力
お前が受け継いだというのか！
The power of the Six Paths!
You inherited it?
こしゃくな！
Ridiculous!
ぐっ…。
皆 アシュラに力を貸してくれ。
Everyone, lend Ashura your power!
父上!?
Father!
アシュラ チャクラとは
多くの人の心をつなぐ絆の力だ。
Ashura, chakra is a power that
can link the hearts of many!
みんな…。
Everyone!
感じるよ… みんなの力を！
I feel it…I can feel…
everyone's…
…power!
なに!?
What?!
なん… だと…。
What is this?
兄さん！
ぐっ… アシュラ！
Elder Brother!
Ashura!
これが 絆の力だ！
This is…
…the power of our bond!
ぐあぁ～！
くっ… うぅ…。
兄さん。
寄るな！
Elder Brother!
Stay away!
アシュラ… 俺は忍宗を…。
Ashura…
I will never…
お前を決して認めぬ！
acknowledge Ninshu…or you!
(兄さん))
Elder Brother…
(ハゴロモ)その後 風の噂でインドラは→
Soon after that,
I heard rumors that Indra established
a sect of Ninjutsu that idealized power.
力を理想とする
忍術の一派を作ったと聞いた。
わしは写輪眼の持つ不遇を
石碑として残した。
I recorded the misfortune that
the Sharingan brings about
in the stone tablet.
しかし それはゼツに利用され→
However, Zetsu took advantage of it
まったくの無駄に
なってしまったようだがな。
and seems to have
been a total waste.
((アシュラ どうやら わしも→
Ashura…
It seems my time in this world
is coming to an end.
天命を
まっとうするときがきたようだ。
父上！
お父様。
おじいちゃん。
Father!
- Father!
- Grandpa!
わしは この世界を
うまく導くことはできなかった。
I was not able to guide
this world well…
そんなことはありません。
That's not true!
父上の意志は
これからも忍宗によって→
We'll pass on your will to many,
many people through Ninshu, Father!
多くの者たちに
伝わっていきます。
だが
そうでない者も残してしまった。
But I leave behind some who will not…
ゆうべ インドラがやってきた。
えっ。
Indra came by last night.
インドラか？
Is that you, Indra?
わしを殺しに来たのか？
Have you come to kill me?
ハッ もう
俺が手を下すまでもなかろう。
There's no need for me
to do that anymore.
俺がここに来たのは→
I came here
これから地獄と化す
忍宗の未来を突きつけるためだ。
to end the future
of this hell disguised as Ninshu.
あなたは ずっと
祖母の力を恐れていた。
You have always feared
the power of my grandmother.
だが その強大な力を直視せず→
And instead of trying to
understand this enormous power,
ただ避けようとしていた。
you merely ran from it…
愛だの絆などという
詭弁を盾にしてな。
using love and bonds as a shield.
あなたの
その身勝手な思い違いが→
Your selfish misconception
will mar the future of Ninshu
忍宗の未来に
戦いと災いを生むのだ。
with wars and calamities.
俺は アシュラとその一族を
そして 忍宗を→
Until I destroy Ashura
and his brethren,
and wipe out Ninshu from
the face of this world,
この世界から滅ぼすまで
永久に戦いをやめるつもりはない。
I have no intention of
ever stopping my fight.
それを成し遂げるためなら→
Until I accomplish this,
俺の魂は何度でも よみがえり
戦い続ける。
my soul will reincarnate and fight,
however long it takes!
すまぬの…。
Forgive me.
父上 ご安心ください。
Father, please be at peace.
兄さんの魂が何度でも
よみがえるのなら→
If Elder Brother's soul will reincarnate
over and over again, so shall mine.
私の魂もまた
何度でも よみがえりましょう。
アシュラ この世界の行方は→
Ashura…
I entrust the future of this world…
お前たちと
その子孫に託すとしよう。
…to you and your descendants…
(アシュラ)父上！
(フタミ)ハゴロモ様！
Father!
Lord Hagoromo!
(カンナ)お父様！
おじいちゃん！))
- Father!
- Grandpa!
(ハゴロモ)そして インドラの宣言どおり
２人の戦いは続いた。
And as Indra warned,
the battle between them waged on,
長く 果てしなく 幾度となく。
その戦いで
憎しみが憎しみを生み→
もはや取り返しのつかぬほどに
膨れ上がっていった。
その戦いは アシュラとインドラが
死んでもなお続いた。
２人の魂は幾度も転生してな。
その末裔が お前
千住柱間と うちはマダラ。
そして 今は
うずまきナルトと うちはサスケだ。
皆の者たちよ。
なんとしても
ナルトとサスケを助け出すのだ。
わしは 確信している。
この２人こそ
長く続いた忍の因縁に→
真実の答えを出してくれると。